This first read me belongs to factory_girl, which is
ينتمي هذا الملف التمهيدي الأول إلى factory_girl، وهو
an open source project maintained by a development shop called thoughtbot.
مشروع مفتوح المصدر يتبناه متجر تنمية يسمى thoughtbot.
Without knowing the specifics of what this project does we can see that this
دون معرفة تفاصيل هذا المشروع، يمكن أن نعرف أن
file is broken up into many small chunks.
هذا الملف يتم تقسيمه إلى العديد من الأجزاء الصغيرة.
Each one of them is very clearly defined and readable.
وكل جزء منها قابل للقراءة ويتم تحديده بوضوح شديد.
At the top we can see some links to more external documentation,
يمكن أن نرى بعض الروابط في الأعلى للحصول على مزيد من المستندات الخارجية،
some installation instructions, and
وبعض إرشادات التثبيت
then underneath we can find some essential additional information
كما يوجد أسفلها بعض المعلومات الإضافية الضرورية
along with information for how we can contribute to the project.
إضافة إلى معلومات عن كيفية المشاركة في المشروع.
At the very bottom is a section that links out to
يوجد في أقصى الجزء السفلي قسم لنقلك إلى
the license and all the licensing information.
الترخيص ومعلومات الترخيص.
So without knowing what factory_girl is or does we can assume that if we wanted
لذلك، دون معرفة ما هو factory_girl أو مهمته، قد نظن أنه عند استخدامه،
to use it we'd have all the information we'd need to get started right here.
يكون لدينا جميع المعلومات التي نحتاجها للبدء الآن.
Next we've got can.viewify, which is a personal project by my friend Kat.
فيما يلي can.viewify، مشروع لصديق لي يدعى كات.
This one is considerably shorter, but
يبدو ذلك أقصر بكثير، لكن
it seems to be structured in a similar way with lots of short, clear sections.
يبدو أنه منظم بطريقة مماثلة مع العديد من الأقسام القصيرة الواضحة.
We've got our description,
لقد حصلنا على الوصف،
we've got our installation instructions, and this is a little different.
وإرشادات التثبيت، إلا أن ذلك يبدو مختلفًا قليلًا.
We've got some usage examples here.
توجد بعض أمثلة الاستخدام هنا.
This readme does not have contribution information, and
لا يحتوي الملف التمهيدي على معلومات عن المساهمة،
instead has a little section on an issue that is known within this code,
ويحتوي على جزء صغير عن مشكلة معروفة في هذا الكود بدلًا من ذلك،
and down at the bottom we once again have some licensing information.
كما يوجد في الجزء السفلي بعض معلومات الترخيص.
Lastly, we've got a readme from Udacity's very
في النهاية، لقد حصلنا على ملف تمهيدي من لعبة صمم مغامرتك الخاصة
own Create-Your-Own-Adventure game, which comes from our Git and
جدًا من Udacity، التي تأتي من الدورة Git
GitHub course, which you should check out if you haven't already.
وGitHub الأمر الذي ينبغي التحقق من توافره لديك بالفعل.
This readme doesn't have too much code necessarily.
لا يحتوي هذا الملف التمهيدي على عدد كبير من الأكواد بالضرورة.
Just that one line there, but it does have a very detailed explanation
يوجد سطر واحد فقط، لكن يوجد توضيح مفصّل جدًا
of how we're supposed to contribute to this repository.
للطريقة التي من المفترض أن نساهم بها في هذا المخزون.
Like the other two readme's we've got some licensing information
لقد حصلنا على بعض معلومات الترخيص في الجزء السفلي أيضًا،
at the bottom as well.
مثلما حدث في الملفين التمهيديين الآخرين.
So, without knowing anything about the actual code within each of these
لذلك، دون معرفة أي شيء عن الكود الفعلي داخل كل مشروع من هذه المشروعات الثلاثة،
projects we can see that all three of these readme's gives us a quick overview
يمكننا معرفة أن جميع الملفات التمهيدية الثلاثة تقدم لنا لمحة سريعة
of the essential information we may need to get these projects up and running.
عن المعلومات الأساسية التي قد نحتاجها لبدء هذه المشروعات وتشغيلها.
In the next few sections we're going to be talking about
في الأقسام التالية، سنتحدث عن
each of these sections in more detail.
كل قسم من هذه الأقسام بالتفصيل.